RIAN MELLOTTE

CONTACT



26B Coltbridge Avenue, Edinburgh, EH12 6AH



07596255923



rianmellotte@hotmail.co.uk



github.com/RianMellotte

SKILLS

- Self-motivated and driven
- Leadership
- · Problem solving
- · Quick and adaptive learner
- Clear and effective communicator
- Working as part of a team
- · Ability to work well under pressure
- Python
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- React
- Git/Github
- Node.js
- NPM

INTERESTS

I am an avid chess player. I have won both individual and team prizes. I have served as a President of QUB chess club and board member on the Ulster Chess Union. Chess has helped me improved my problem solving skills, patience and concentration. I also have a keen interest in learning Spanish. I studied Spanish at GCSE and attended an extracurricular course at QUB to improve this skill further. I also use the Duolingo to help develop my vocabulary.

REFERENCES

References To be provided upon request.

Experience working in various technical and detail focused roles. Passionate about technology and recently become enamoured with software development. I offer a unique perspective, having studied creative problem solving through philosophy and chess. Determined to work hard to learn and develop my skills in programming, through both work and self-study.

EXPERIENCE

September 2019 to Current

Developer

- First class mark for Masters Python module.
- Built Python database analyser and text to speech synthesiser.
- Completed course in web development using technologies including HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Git/Github, Node.js, NPM and PostgresSQL amongst others.
- Built and deployed facial recognition app, accessible at: https://facerecognition411.herokuapp.com
- Currently completing courses, including advanced Javascript, advanced web development and machine learning.

September 2018 to September 2019

Associate PwC Operate

- Financial Crime Analyst for a large investment bank.
- Compiled relevant data, quickly and effectively assessed it, and recorded my findings.
- Used analytical skills to ensure that the data did not contain discrepancies and that all of the procedural requirements were met.
- Delivered a number of training sessions to my team.

January 2018 to April 2018

Political Consultancy Intern Stratagem NI

- Conducted research and compiled reports for various projects and clients.
- Led office hospitality and assisted in office and event management.
- Developed many skills including researching, event management and business management.
- Used initiative both as a researcher and on a number of projects I led or assisted on.

September 2014 to October 2015

Technical Support Advisor Teleperformance

- Assisted customers in dealing with any technical issues they were experiencing and dealt with any complaints they had.
- Quickly devised workarounds for any new problems to ensure that the customer was left with a satisfactory solution.
- Supervised newer colleagues and dealt with customers who wanted their call to be escalated.
- Received positive reviews and spot prizes for excellent customer service and hard work.

EDUCATION

MSc Mind, Language and Embodied Cognition University of Edinburgh

Classification yet to be awarded. Completed in August 2020.

BA Joint Honours Philosophy and Politics Queen's University Belfast

First Class with Degree Plus. Completed in June 2018.